Philip Bergman Papers
Philip Bergman Papers
- Media, 1968-1995
  - Moving image, 1968-1995
    - Individual Bergman stories (for various programs)
      - North-Vincent, 08/31/1970; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 2:12; bergman_p_094 (Box 9)
      - No Smoking (ABC News), Film, 16mm, color negative, sound, 50 feet; bergman_p_174 (Box 22)
      - Old Folks (Koppel 2/28), 02/28/1979; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 3:30; bergman_p_095 (Box 9)
      - Pancake Maker (Dub from History) (World News Tonight), 05/18/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_096 (Box 5)
      - Phone Ripofff (ABC News) [with Ted Koppel], Film, 16mm, color, sound, 100 feet; bergman_p_175 (Box 22)
      - Reasoner Presentation, 06/28/1978; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_097 (Box 5)
      - Reynolds/Cuba/McGovern, 05/07/1975; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_098 (Box 9)
      - Second to None, Parts 1-11 (Ted Koppel) (World News Tonight: Special Assignment), 06/07/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_099 (Box 5)
      - Sex in Office, Parts 1-3 (Sherr) (World News Tonight), 06/05/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_100 (Box 5)
      - Strasburg RR, Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_101 (Box 9)
      - Stress: Are We Killing Ourselves? (World News Tonight) (Aired 5/1-5/4), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_102 (Box 5)
      - Tapes of Wrath, 09/11/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_103 (Box 5)
      - Telephone (Saturday News), 01/30/1976; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_104 (Box 9)
      - TV Ratings, Parts 1-3, 10/23/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_105 (Box 5)
      - Two Income Family, Parts 1-3 (World News Tonight) (Aired 5/29-5/31), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_106 (Box 5)
      - Victims of Crime (Dub of FT 1139-90), 03/16/1990; Videotape, VHS, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_107 (Box 10)
      - Bergman Clips (Telephone, Elderly), 09/14/1976; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_108 (Box 5)
      - Bergman Dub No. 2: Wayne Newton Profile (3:00), Fanconia College (3:30), Profile Kid Handicapper (2:59), Elderly (2:37), Grants Bankruptcy (4:50), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_109 (Box 5)
      - Phil Bergman Magazine, World News Tonight, Nightline Pieces (Resume 5), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_110 (Box 5)
    - Nightline stories
      - Boy and Gorilla (TK Open and Spot) (Nightline 01/17/1986), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_111 (Box 5)
      - Boy and Gorilla (TK Open and Spot) (Nightline 01/17/1986), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_112 (Box 5)
      - Children of War (Nightline 11/09/1984) [1], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 4:00; bergman_p_113 (Box 5)
      - Children of War (Nightline 11/09/1984) [2], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 4:00; bergman_p_114 (Box 5)
      - Children of War (Nightline 11/09/1984)/Farmer's Profile (Nightline 01/17/1985) [1], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_115 (Box 5)
      - Children of War (Nightline 11/09/1984)/Farmer's Profile (Nightline 01/17/1985) [2], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_116 (Box 5)
      - Farmers (Nightline 01/17/1985) [1], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_117 (Box 5)
      - Farmers (Nightline 01/17/1985) [2], Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_118 (Box 5)
      - Farmers: Disappearing Towns (Nightline), 03/14/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_119 (Box 5)
      - Galapagos/Caras (Nightline 05/10/1985), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_120 (Box 6)
      - Heart Transplant Patients ("Insider") (Nightline 12/13/1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_121 (Box 6)
      - Heart Transplant Revisited (Pentaque) (Nightline), 06/12/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_122 (Box 6)
      - Heart Transplant (Spot from Pre-Tape with Chyrons) (Nightline), 10/21/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_123 (Box 6)
      - Homeless (Petaque) (Nightline), 02/14/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 8:02; bergman_p_124 (Box 6)
      - Homeless (Screening) (Nightline), 10/17/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 5:01; bergman_p_125 (Box 6)
      - Homeless (Koppel Lead-in with Chyrons) (Nightline), 12/04/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_126 (Box 6)
      - Star Spangled Banner (Nightline), 07/04/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_127 (Box 6)
      - Nightline Dubs: Farm Family (1/17/85), Galapagos (5/10/85), Heart Transplant (10/21/85), Homeless (12/4/85), 01/17/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_128 (Box 6)
      - Nightline Spots: Zimmerman (5/31/83), Spelling Bee (6/8-6/9), 05/31/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_129 (Box 6)
      - Nightline 12/23/1985, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_130 (Box 6)
    - Research and background material
      - The American Dread Nought (258 38 DN) (unclassified) (Calvin Communications No. 431591), Film, 16mm, color negative, sound, 1200 feet; bergman_p_176 (Box 22)
      - [Battleships] ((Fox 2513) (1), Film, 35mm, black and white, sound, 100 feet; bergman_p_180 (Box 22)
      - Battleships No. 1 (Film Transfer), 03/02/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_137 (Box 6)
      - Battleships No. 3 (Film Transfer), 03/03/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_138 (Box 6)
      - Becky Sharp Promo Reel, 11/02/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_139 (Box 6)
      - Bonnie and Clyde (1st Hour) (Film Transfer), 02/18/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_140 (Box 6)
      - Butch Cassidy Scenes/Great Train Robbery (Film Transfer) [2 cassettes], 09/02/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 40:00; bergman_p_141 (Box 6)
      - Casablanca No. 1 (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_142 (Box 6)
      - Casablanca No. 2 (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_143 (Box 6)
      - Couples in Conflict, Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_144 (Box 10)
      - Dachau Concentration Camp (Pathe News footage), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_145 (Box 7)
      - The Day All Hell Broke Loose (National Center for Atmospheric Research and FAA), Videotape, VHS, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_146 (Box 10)
      - Film Preservation Project (UCLA Film and TV Archive), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 4:50; bergman_p_147 (Box 7)
      - Festival of Preservation 1988 (UCLA Film and TV Archive), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_148 (Box 7)
      - Festival of Preservation 1989 (UCLA Film and TV Archive), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_149 (Box 7)
      - Friendship One, Videotape, VHS, dub, 80:00; bergman_p_150 (Box 10)
      - Gag Reel No. 5 (unbleeped) (ABC News), Film, 16mm, color, sound, 300 feet; bergman_p_177 (Box 22)
      - Galapagos Islands No. 1 (Film Transfer), 05/01/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_151 (Box 7)
      - Galapagos Islands No. 2 (Film Transfer), 05/01/1985; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_152 (Box 7)
      - In Defense of Freedom (Department of Defense), 05/09/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_153 (Box 7)
      - Joe Louis Highlights (Braddock, Schmeling, Galento, Marciano) (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_154 (Box 7)
      - Kennedy-Nixon Debate, Part 1, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_155 (Box 7)
      - Kennedy-Nixon Debate, Part 4, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_156 (Box 7)
      - Miss Jones, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_157 (Box 7)
      - Muppet Movie, Part 1 (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_158 (Box 7)
      - Muppet Movie, Part 2 (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_159 (Box 7)
      - Monster Truck Promotional Footage (US Hot Rod Association), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_160 (Box 7)
      - Nazi Concentration Camps, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_161 (Box 7)
      - New York-New York (ABC News) (664-66), Film, 16mm, black and white, sound, 1200 feet; bergman_p_178 (Box 22)
      - NFL Clips (GMA), 01/12/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_162 (Box 7)
      - NFL Funnies, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_163 (Box 8)
      - NFL Hits, 01/09/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_164 (Box 8)
      - Perils of Pauline (Film Transfer), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_165 (Box 8)
      - Playmate Workout Home Video, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_166 (Box 8)
      - Public Enement (1st Hour) (Film Transfer), 02/13/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_167 (Box 8)
      - Secret Fight Marciano-Clay, Film, 16mm, black and white, sound, 200 feet; bergman_p_179 (Box 22)
      - Skydivers 1, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_168 (Box 8)
      - Skydivers 2, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_169 (Box 8)
      - Sport/Olympics (Funny Black and White Shots), 07/18/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_170 (Box 8)
      - A Strategy of Avoidance (National Center for Atmospheric Research and FAA), Videotape, VHS, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_171 (Box 10)
      - Who's On First (Abbot and Costello), 02/07/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_172 (Box 8)
    - Jules Bergman video
      - Jules Bergman (Sunday World News with Sam Donaldson), 02/15/1987; Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_131 (Box 10)
      - Jules Bergman Obit (CNN), 02/12/1987; Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_132 (Box 10)
      - Jules Bergman Obit (NBC, CBS, ABC), 02/12/1987; Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_133 (Box 10)
      - Jules Bergman Obit (Nightline), 02/12/1987; Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_134 (Box 10)
      - Jules Bergman Obit (World News Tonight, Newsome, GMA, Nightline), 02/12/1987; Videotape, VHS, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_135 (Box 10)
      - Jules Bergman Week (3/20/95-3/24/95), 03/20/1995; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_136 (Box 10)
- Papers, 1956-1995
  - Awards (Oversize 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 11-12)
    Includes: political convention press materials (1964, 1976), the Reagan Inauguration press kit (1981), President Nixon's Belgium trip press kit (1974), patriotic sheet music and 45's, ABC Network publicity material, ABC field tape recorder, printed material.
  - Personal papers (Box 13-15)
    Includes: correspondence, family photos, college journalism work and papers, military service records, military service journalism work, writings.
  - Photography (Box 17-18, Oversize 2)
    Prints and negatives. Includes photographs related to early journalism work (college and military).
  - Professional papers (Box 12, 15-16)
    Correspondence, ABC memos and programming data, Phil Bergman publicity and clips, press credentials, program research materials and binders.
  - Reporter's notebooks (Box 19-20)
    Original field notebooks related to Phil Bergman-produced stories.